can you buy
[Music]
continuing with our series on the grace
of God
today I want to talk mainly about
the manifestations
of the grace of God
our main text that we have been using is
First Corinthians chapter 1 verse 1 to
verse 9 in the new King James version
and in reads as follows Paul called to
be an apostle of Jesus Christ through
the will of God and Trust And as our
brother
to the Church of God which is at Corinth
to those who are Sanctified in Christ
Jesus going to be Saints with all who in
every place call on the name of Jesus
our lord both days and Ours verse 3
grace to you
and peace from God our Father and the
Lord Jesus Christ and on our main text I
thank my God always concerning you for
the grace of God which was given to you
note Grace is always given
it's a gift that God gives
you don't snatch it away
you don't wrestle it out of God's hand
it is given
he says to these Christians in Corinth
he's celebrating concerning these
Corinthians and he says I thank my God
always because when I look at you I see
the grace of God that was given to you
by Jesus Christ and then verse 5 he
talks how that Grace was manifested he
says that you were enriched in
everything by Him in all utterance and
all knowledge
it's a very important thing for us to
note why Paul is saying what he is
saying in the first week we did give the
background of Corinth what a place it
was
and how much there was so much evil in
that place but in the words of Paul
these women and men in the church at
Corinth had experienced the grace of God
somehow this grace that was given
changed them so dramatically that they
didn't look like the same people of all
the churches that Paul wrote to this is
the only church where Paul says they
were enriched in Gifts of utterance this
is the only church that moved in the
power of God in the gifts of the Spirit
that we read about in First Corinthians
chapter 12. you know the church in
Ephesus was an incredible church but
even the church in Ephesus could not
equal the church in Corinth the church
in Antioch it's a model church we use
that church as theologians to model what
we do in church after the church in
Antioch but even the church in Antioch
could never equal the church in Corinth
to think that this church in Corinth was
born amidst a place that had so much
wrong so much evil going on so many gods
that were worshiped in this place it
been a place that was like Center of
people that came from all over the world
because of the pot that it had and it
became a Melting Pot of different
cultures and where people did all kinds
of things it was a place when you were
in Corinth you know people just let
loose they did whatever they liked and
in the church like that the grace of God
is extended among those people people
who their former life was so wrong and
it's so evil and yet Paul says when I
look at you you don't look the same
you're so different and that Grace can
be seen on you because it has changed
you and when I come to your church I
love visiting you because in the church
you are enriched in all things there's
Gifts of power there's Gifts of
utterance there's Gifts of knowledge
there the anointing is moving and yet
when I look at you I Marvel at what the
grace of God can do can I hear a good
amen look at somebody and say the grace
of God is amazing
the grace of God is amazing so this is
what Grace was interestingly used
by Paul because he borrowed from Greek
mythology and from what the Greeks were
practicing in those days you know I had
one preacher during the week I was
listening to him and he said something
that I never thought of you know when
you know it in the time of Paul a good
part of the world was Greek speaking at
the time because the Greeks you know
they had imported their culture to many
parts of the world and the language of
Greek was spoken extensively and so the
the New Testament as such was written in
the Greek language
but what is also interesting is that the
Greek language on its own is such a rich
language
that it's it seems like it's the only
language at that time that could fully
Express
what God is doing in our lives let me
give you one example we have the word
comforter that the holy spirit is called
comforter you know the the King James
Bible says you know I'll give you
another comforter in Greek it is the
word paracletus but when you study that
word paratletos it has a seven-fold
meaning it means comforter strengthener
stand by it means teacher guide
counselor Advocate he's got seven words
I've remembered six there's one more I
don't know which one maybe you will help
me with the one more
so you must help me because
I'm sorry about that
and helper yeah you just helped me with
the helper all right so so so you know
it's amazing how God is able to engineer
things in such a way and not only that
in the Greek culture they had a belief
that the gods because they they believed
in many gods they had a belief that if
the gods touched somebody
this person who would be touched by the
gods they would receive a special
Charisma Charisma is simply from the
word they would receive a special
Charisma Charisma is simply a gift given
by Grace they believed when the gods
touched you they imparted to you a Grace
and this grace
manifested in your life being better
your behavior been better it even went
so far as your giftings would be better
in other words they said when the gods
touched you it was such a magical touch
and you came under their spell and when
Grace touched you you became a totally
transformed person so different that you
acted differently you spoke differently
you had different gifts and people who
looked at you couldn't tell that you are
the same person so when Paul was trying
to teach about what Christ had done in
the lives of the the Corinthians he
borrowed from Greek mythology and he
said you have received Grace now we know
that it is not the gods who have touched
us we know that it is their God who has
touched us and when the God has touched
us there is Grace that is imparted Upon
Our Lives tell your neighbor there's
Grace on your life
tell them again there's Grace on your
life
and so what I want to do this morning I
want us to explore several scriptural
passages that further explain this Grace
so that you can understand it and so
that you can notice it you don't need
any extra thing to be done to you
because the grace of God is already upon
your life
Bible says in Ephesians chapter 2 verse
8 for by Grace we have been saved
through faith it says and that is not of
yourself it is the gift of God
so Grace is on your life and the reason
I want to go through these scriptures is
that there are many of God's people who
are walking in the grace of God Mara
abeko our way
what we want we don't want this word
grace to be an academic word just a
religious word where we mentally Ascend
to the fact that we have Grace I want
you as you look at your life unfold in
different times and differences and you
can say that's the touch of God that's
the touch of God that's the touch of God
can I hear a good amen in the house and
that's the touch of God and so first of
all I want us to start in First
Corinthians chapter one from our main
text
Paul says I thank my God always
concerning you Corinthians
for the grace of God which was given to
you
so Grace here is the empowering Touch Of
God which always comes what's this in a
visible way
it comes in demonstrated manifestation
in other words wherever Grace is
it is visible you can sin you can see it
Grace it's never silent it's not
something that we mentally assent to
when Grace come it puts the divine power
of God upon you such that you start
thinking differently acting differently
and you manifest the gifts of God
abilities that you never had before so
in other words when Grace comes it
spills over into every aspect of Our
Lives when you read First Corinthians 18
this is where we see when Paul
established the church in Corinth but in
chapter 18 he doesn't make any mention
of the miraculous power or the Charis or
the gifts of Grace and yet when he
writes to them in First Corinthians 2 he
talks about this he sends to them when I
came to you Corinthians in spite of your
background in spite of who you were in
spite of everything the grace of God
came upon you and when I came to you I
didn't want to come and preach to you
with the Excellency of man's speech I
didn't come with a well-crafted speech
but I came in demonstration of the
spirit and of power and it says the
reason I wanted it to be in
demonstration of the spirit and of power
because I want your faith not to rest in
my nice speech but I want your faith to
rest in the power of God
that word demonstration means something
that is done to a point where it draws
attention to you Paul says when I preach
the message of the cross the power of
God Came Upon you in the form of the
grace of God and this Grace came to you
in a demonstrative way it was sin it was
demonstrated It Came Upon Your Life to
draw attention listen to this when God
begins to work in your life it will
begin to draw the attention of other
people
because they know you in your past they
know your background they know how far
you went at school they know how much
you are earning Mara they can't
reconcile what they are saying now to
what they know about you so God is
simply saying I have put Grace upon them
because I want to demonstrate
what I can do in somebody's life and
Paul says I came in that demonstration
of the spirit and of power in other
words Paul is saying when I preached God
authenticated this message with signs
and wonders God made sure he puts a
stamp of approval because when we preach
it is not a waste of time it is a time
for God to demonstrate His science and
this science and wonders left people
baffled bewildered
astonished and at a loss of words that's
what that word wonders mean it means
they were baffled bewildered so there
are people when they look at you they
just can't reconciled in Toca when you
know they can't explain why you are
where you are in life they understand
they know that you come from a broken
home they know that you were poor at
your home now they know at school you
were not doing well or not what number
last but when they look at you there's
something upon your life that is totally
different and so they are left baffled
bewildered and they don't know what to
say they are astonished they're at the
loss of words because God is
demonstrating through you tell your
neighbor God is demonstrating through
you God is demonstrating through you
so Paul is saying this gospel that we
are preaching is not an intellectual
message this gospel we are preaching is
not there to entertain you but this
gospel that we are preaching becomes in
Supernatural power and it demonstrates
something that can be seen in the case
of the Corinthians what could be seen
other spiritual gifts that we read about
in First Corinthians chapter 12. so when
Grace touches us it makes us different
to what we have been before
now the change might not happen
immediately
but the change will happen finally
and it's a change that is measurable
it's a change that it's visible in other
words we are not here to play Church
we are here to sit under the umbrella of
the grace of God I may not change this
year Mara watch the space next year I'm
not gonna be the same person again we
are here sitting under the crystal you
know some of you you don't you realize
that something about you has changed
something about you has changed you are
no longer moon like you used to be mono
tell your neighbor he's talking about
you
no longer silent like you used to be
silent
you realize that the way you think about
your life you have purpose you have
goals now you have you have Destiny now
you want to do something with your life
you know you know am I talking to people
who are alive here you no longer you're
no longer thinking the same way
foreign
you'll notice you live above sin Billy
hey I know now you say yes
saying you but here you are today
here you are today
and so God when his grace comes Upon Our
Lives it changes us and that's why so we
need to be grateful for the grace of God
yeah
and let's not forget that Grace is to be
made available to all people
secondly in Acts chapter 4 verse 33
something else is said about Grace
it says as the apostles went out to
preach
acts 4 33 it says and with great power
somebody say great power
say it again
and with great power
gave the apostles witness of the
resurrection of the Lord Jesus Christ
and watch eating and great grace was
upon them all read it with me ring and
great
say it again
so you note in that scripture there are
measures of Grace
this great grace there's Grace there's
great grace there's another kind of
Grace
but here's the point I want to raise
these apostles
they went out preaching
the Bible says God put Grace on them
and when he put Grace on these Apostles
as they preached as they gave witness of
the Lord Jesus Christ there was great
power in manifestations now I can
understand that because you see when you
go around preaching it is not everywhere
where you get results
sometimes you can preach in a place
outside my encourage you were never
there and Paul is saying when you went
out preaching
this Grace came and enveloped you
and when this Grace comes upon you it
gives you results so that you have
results in what you labor in I don't
know many of you
you can have all the right script
every eye dotted every T crossed and
never get the results
and Paul is saying the Bible is saying
when Grace is upon you you will get the
results I see you getting results
wherever you go in your life because
great grace is upon you
and so this expression great grace it
tells us the effects of Grace in other
words when Grace touched them when Grace
Came Upon them when it became a mighty
Touch Of God they were successful in
their Enterprise
don't ever look down upon success don't
ever take success for granted it doesn't
come every day
even if things might be where they ought
to be and you have all your ducks in a
row and everything lined up properly you
might not enjoy success but when you see
success come then you know that great
grace is upon you I see great grace upon
your life
number three
in Acts 11 23
the Bible speaks of Barnabas going to
the church in Antioch he visited the
Believers in Antioch note what it says
it says and when he came
and had seen the grace of God
he was led so which means the grace of
God can be seen
it's something that can be seen
something that can be witnessed in other
words it's not just something that can
be believed
it's not something that we only know in
our heads it is something that not only
can it be sin others can testify about
it
blame your family members when they come
to you for counseling and they ask you
to pray for them there's something
everybody
they may not admit to it they may not
say so mother there's something
everybody belong in you that you
yourself don't see in you because the
grace of God can be seen you know when
they talk they say but you know we may
not agree with this thing
there is something or better still some
others come to you say Yes somewhere
and because
[Applause]
it's the grace of God upon my life can I
hear a good amen no it's not because
it's not because I have any special
thing it's not because I'm any special
person it's because of the grace of God
if it was not because of the grace of
God I wouldn't be having what I'm having
I wouldn't be doing what I'm doing
somebody says the grace of God upon my
life is the grace of God
and Barnabas when he went he sees these
Christians in Antioch and he says I can
see something is different about you
you know you know it's amazing even when
you are young
when the grace of God is upon you it can
be seen
and you have even older people
responding to your leadership
the nice thing about the grace of God
and the favor of God is that even if
Allah
when the grace is upon you
you remember you remember you remember
Joseph when he was in prison Orange
but even if we are very orange when the
grace of God is upon you the Bible says
and and and the king the leader Pharaoh
when he saw Joseph in prison he saw that
the favor of God the grace of God is
upon him and he realized that wherever
Joseph is the favor follows because when
favor is on you it follows you wherever
you go he says he took Joseph and he put
him in charge because he saw so God
gives you a position that you don't
deserve because the grace of God is upon
you because it can be seen yeah you can
see it okay say it I mean he was the
same job with somebody
you are from the same school Lane when
you look at the outcomes of your life
they are much more further than you
oh am I am I talking to people who are
alive here and the problem is you can't
compete with somebody upon whom the
grace of God is because it's not going
to help you you work the whole night and
one other asleep in the whole night but
when you look at the outcomes that are
further than you I see the grace of God
upon your life in Jesus name can I hear
a good amen if you don't say Amen the
children will say amen and I love them
the grace of God is upward my sermon is
so powerful
and some of you are not even saying amen
Where You Are don't worry neh they are
okay kids are okay here I don't I don't
mind they can if these adults don't say
Amen let the children run Jesus
[Applause]
Grace is upon her
bless the Lord
but Grace can be seen number four
Romans chapter 12.
verse 6. I love this one Paul writes to
the Romans
heaven then gifts
differing
according to the grace that is given to
us you see grace is given
um decides to give us
gifts
I'm going to show you later there's
nobody who's left out you see some of
you you you you you you feel like you
are not gifted
and you think you're not gifted because
you you know you you know I hate people
who said no I've never had any gifts
I've never been good in anything or
wrong or son
it says Heaven than gifts what's what it
says differing
so everybody has a gift or gifts usually
it's more than one and it's different to
your neighbor tell your neighbor I'm so
glad I don't look like you
and I'm not like you just tell them I'm
so glad I'm not like you
uh
but look at look at your partners I'm so
glad I'm not like you
and listen what Paul says heaven then
gifts differing watch according to the
grace that is given to us let us use
them
the word gifts is charismata
in other words there are these Charis
matters this Grace gifts note they have
been given to us by the grace of God in
other words you don't have to work for
it
and if you got it don't boast about it
because it didn't work for it in the
first place
so it is gifts differing in other words
we've received a touch of Grace and God
has given us special empowering of his
presence and the special empowering of
the presence of God manifest in these
spiritual gifts because he impact this
Charisma the ability to move in this
particular giftings and then he says
when you have that gift
use it
why because your gift is not for your
benefits
[Music]
you see some of you you have gifts but
you are sitting on them
I mean look at it you know turned out
leading us here
she's singing so well our worship leader
she sings over can you imagine if we
didn't have that gift being used for the
benefit of everybody
in the shower
I'm nothing without you
with it's not gonna benefit anybody
but my goodness when she sings we all
join our hearts in prayer and in worship
towards God
oh come on let's give the Lord a big
hand
[Applause]
don't you just like that love voice
it's nice in church right
but can you imagine
going to help you
so I'm gonna help you
what am I saying that some of you that
communities are waiting for you
to give leadership because you have the
gift of leadership
that you receive by the grace of God
you're not using it
yeah
yeah you're sitting on it some of you
you have administrative skills
some of you you are gifted to work with
people you know I've realized it's not
everybody who's good with working with
people some people are good working with
machines
because because it's because emission a
machine doesn't care the mood you are in
it's a machine when you press a computer
it doesn't say hammer you're in a bad
mood ah even Siri doesn't say hey
recalculating you're in a bad mood today
you know but there are people who are
good with people you just know how and
I've never understood companies you know
in their front desk
you know in the reception there
yeah now you know you can feel me now
right you can feel me now up until that
time you were not saying amen now you
can feel me
oh what about the people who are working
more Modi call center
and some of these people you know
sometimes
you wish you could say something as
Apollo song to them anybody knows what
I'm talking about eh
I've never wondered why we have so many
misplaced people in the world
but that's the reason why we have so
many unfulfilled people in the world
I'll come to that later in the sermon
because they're in the wrong spot
they are operating in the area where
they don't have Grace
foreign
and Paul says Hi corner we have these
Grace gifts
that have been given to us
but which means because it's a great
gift Mama because it's a Grace gift
you can succeed where others are failing
oh yeah
you get a guy with a leadership gift or
a girl with a leadership gift you take
them to a company that's not working and
in a year's time they've turned the
company around and is profitable again
take somebody who doesn't have a gift
they take a profitable company but yet
they ever bankrupt
because they are misplaced people ask
your neighbor are you misplaced
I hope not
number what
Outlast number water
number five First Corinthians 3 10 Paul
says I love this one I love this one
he says according
to the grace of God
which was given to me
as a wise master builder
I have laid the foundation
and another Builds on it
that expression
according to the grace of God which is
given to me in the original you can
better translate it as follows Paul is
saying
being dominated by the touch of God in
my life
I became a wise master builder
being dominated now this is important
because Paul is writing to the
Corinthians
remember what we said about him when he
came to the church in Corinth he saw
something that was different
Paul is actually saying
I came to a point where Grace Came Upon
my life even if I've been preaching all
along
I could preach but I couldn't build a
stable Church
I couldn't build anything that's
sustainable I couldn't build anything
that was there that was flourishing but
something happened to me Grace were
important to me and when Grace was
impacted to me I was able to build not
only did I become a builder I became a
wise master builder I was able to build
something that is sustainable something
that is there he says it's an ability
that I didn't have before but when I was
dominated by this Grace I was equipped
with the ability to be able to build
this is important to me because as
you've heard me give the testimony when
I was prayed for on the 4th of September
1983 I remember when God's anointing
Came Upon My Life
I was asking God God what is this
God said this is the anointing
to Pastor a church I didn't understand
it back then as I understand now but I
can tell you for sure from that day
I was able
to build a church now when I say I not
mean my power God helping me but I was
able to know what will make a church
work
Amazon
even if I've been to Bible School
even if I've studied theology
it's another thing to build a church
many of you know even if you
can dance and know everything about
Finance it's another thing to run a
business
you need a Grace
ah you're not hearing what I'm saying
you need address and from that day I
somehow knew supernaturally how we must
run a church what we must do how we must
plan and funnily enough when we did it
it did it
when we did it it worked and so this is
what I want to bring to you
funny
that many of the people not most of them
but there are several people who are
leading in many sectors where you find
that the sector that are leading in they
never studied for it
now come on let's talk I don't know why
I'm standing this side let's talk
let's talk
or even better still I know even in
Ministry it's even worse even in
business there are many people in
Ministry in business who actually never
went to school
Peter and John were appointed case the
Bible says about them when they when
they when they when the sun had dreamed
and the religious leads us caught them
and they brought them before the courts
trying to persecute them they knew that
they were uneducated men
Mara they took note that they had been
with Jesus
so even if they didn't go to school
there there is something that they are
doing that for sure this is not because
of their knowledge there's his grace
upon their life can I hear a good amen
now now just in case you think I'm
saying education is not important that's
not what I'm saying it's very important
what I'm trying to say is this get
educated in line with your grace gift
[Applause]
because if you don't do that oftentimes
we have people who've got certificates
and they can write the best thesis you
can ever get in an area Mara they can
function practically in the same area
man I'm trying to help you
I'm trying to help you there are many
people who are who are great in terms of
Finance they can't even run a business
they're unemployed they don't know and
then you have the guy down the road
and they're running a credible business
and they're doing well why because of
the grace of God oh I see the grace of
God upon your life forces Paul says when
the grace Came Upon me I became a master
builder and I loved the way he uses the
word Billet because in life you build a
Ministry you build a career you build a
home you build a business it's building
it's a it's a process it takes long it
takes time it involves process it
involves different things and different
seasons it means you must be strategic
it means you must think it means you
must bring others on board I see you
building and it's the grace that helps
us to build
[Applause]
it's Grace that helps us build
it's easy to destroy what somebody has
built it's easy to divide a church and
take members and run away with it it's
easy to divide somebody's business and
take away their customers listen to me
you can take away their customers but
you cannot take away their Grace
[Applause]
you can take away what they've done you
can steal all every everything about
them Mario you can't steal what God has
placed upon them
[Applause]
was telling me you know and he shared it
here but he was telling him in detail in
his church he had a huge division in the
church
one of his closest leaders who was very
close here
senior leader
broke away with 22 churches
yeah 22 churches we went there to tell
people 22 churches
so when I was talking to him he says
Bishop
those he said now we have 22 more
churches
and more
he says we have planted again more than
22 and he said something that I liked he
said in the atmosphere Montana is
different
you see things that have been taken by a
coup
they may be them are their environment
is not a nice one
the presence absent
[Applause]
I am not part of your oh oh all the
better yet
[Applause]
Paul says when Grace came it helped me
to be a builder
be aware of where God uses you to be a
builder
because it's by the grace it's not every
time it's not all the time where people
are able to succeed where you are
succeeding it's not always whether able
to handle what you're handling it's not
always where when it has been broken
it's able to rise again it is not always
from defeat and you're able to stand on
your feet it's not always where you
start something
in your pocket when you run your
business from a room or from a garage
that you see it's unlockable it is not
always it can only happen
when Grace is upon your life
because it's Grace that helps you build
can I hear a good amen
can I hear a good amen I see you as a
builder in the name of Jesus
because of the grace of God somebody
shout grace of God upon me
this is why therefore I respect a
calling
whatever area God calls you into
I respect the calling
because God will never call you
without equipping you
and this is why everybody that God calls
most of them felt unqualified
for what they are called Moses says who
am I
Jeremiah said I'm just a child Isaiah
said I'm a man of unclean lips Gideon
said I come from a poverty stricken home
can number last because when God calls
he is not calling you because of what
you possess he is calling you for what
he's going to put upon you and when God
calls you he's going to equip you I see
God equipping you for everything
[Applause]
and that's the problem of being
misplaced
or being in the wrong thing
doing what you were never called for
because if you are never called for it
there's no equipment for it
so you just have to steal other people's
ideas
you just have to save our lawyer
you just have to try and take away what
they've done and criticize what they've
done and run down what they've done
because with all your best efforts you
just can't equal them
but when the grace is on you
it does more than what you're expecting
here's another thing when you operate in
your grace you get more results with
less work
you do this much God does this much
because when Grace comes upon you
it's a sign and a Wonder Woman
I see that Grace upon your life but when
Grace is not upon your life
and when you are in an area where Grace
is not released
you feel uncomfortable
because
I see grace upon your life
in the name of Jesus number six
number six
in First Corinthians 15 10 Paul writes
so much about Grace in The Book of
Corinthians
he writes to them he says
but by the grace of God
I am what I am
and his grace
towards me was not in vain
but I labored more abundantly than they
all yet not I
but the grace of God in Me
let me break that verse down for you you
know most people read this verse and say
yeah I wanna I'm not living right things
are not going well I'm losing I am what
I am by the grace of God
Ah that's not what Paul is saying
no that's not what Paul is saying Paul
says
I used to kill people
mad at them
trying to stop them I'll bring you wrong
but on that day
as I had the letters
from the chief priests
to persecute Christians God met me on my
way to Damascus
and he struck me off my horse and I had
an encounter with a life-saving power of
Jesus Christ and the grace of God
and from that day God started a process
of molding me and shaping me and
training me and changing me when I look
at what I used to be and when I look at
what I am now I can definitely say I am
what I am but the grace of God might
make a move that's not who I was but
when I look what I where I am it was not
because of my intelligence it was all
because of the grace of God I am what I
am by the grace of God
Paul says you see me starting churches
you see me preaching the gospel you see
people being healed you see signs and
wonders you see me traveling all over
the world you see me writing all these
books to all the different churches even
the ability to write so many books I am
what I am
ha by the grace of God
but then he says and his grace that I
receive from him was not in vain
Paul Paul says you know God can give
Grace and put Grace on your life but it
can all be in vain
why it becomes in vain when you don't
operate in it
what Dr Miles has said so many people go
into the grave and take books they
should have written businesses they
should have started Enterprises that
should have been there they take their
gifts and their abilities into the grave
because when they lived they were in the
wrong spot
in the words of Paul they never operated
in their Grace
no when Grace came it was not in vain
I'm doing what the Grace has imparted
upon my life watch he says I'm working
so hard you know what it's really not I
who's working
is the grace of God in Me He says when
you see me overworking myself right when
you see me waking up in the morning and
going to bed at night I think it gets
easier is this Grace Helen Moon I just
can't stop doing what I'm doing I don't
even have to be paid to do what I'm
doing
I don't know where I get all these ideas
I don't know where I get all this
ability I don't know why I'm so
motivated but it's because this grace in
me
because when I serve in my area of Grace
I am a bit
I feel anointed I feel strong
and this is why we have people today who
work half-heartedly
because they're misplaced
when they're supposed to knock off at
four at 3 30.
1530.
if they are operating a a call center
they are no longer taking calls
look at your neighbor and say about a
bishop um
if they're working at home affairs
come on now let's talk come on come on
why because you see we have this
mentality
you know so you uh
no passion
no connection to what you're doing
even what you're doing with your hands
it's not where your gifts lie
it's not where your passion is
so there's nothing in here that makes
you to want to work longer work harder
work with Excellence Angie
but when you are in your area of Grace
this grace
will make you work even if nobody
recognizes and nobody but you are not
listening to what I'm saying
I can tell you of the many ministers I
know many many ministers who have
studied churches many many of them
particularly those who were pioneers and
many pioneers of businesses
many of them spent so much into the
business
and never leave the rewards of it for
many years
put all the money
because when you are in your area of
Grace
you will sacrifice everything
yeah you're not quick to rip the fruit
because you are building tell your
neighbor your building
yeah you understand that you're building
you build it and very often the founder
the the the the the the the leader who
whatever you entitled you want to give
to them the company can't pay them
enough
because there's a lot more they do
outside of the prescribed office hours
yeah
but some of you when you are when you're
unemployed the first question is how
much are you going to give me
now
no Grace
next thing is what is your plan for my
for my for my
for my career development
when I started reading the church nobody
asked me how much did I want to be paid
nobody nobody asked me
nobody nobody actually nobody asked me
for the first three years I never got
paid
and nobody asked why I'm not paid
I have an issue to settle guys
[Applause]
nobody use the garage at home
I was in the garage go higher as an
office
my sister volunteered as my PA my first
PA she was never paid to
why was I run Grace
something in you
she woke up she woke up in the morning
one day one day you know one day I I had
had somebody who came in as a PA Mara
motona icon
IC you know we were supposed to start at
eight half past eight I was okay nine
years old some of you
I think the holy spirit is helping
somebody
and those of you are employers I'm
trying to sort out these issues for you
late and then next thing they don't do
the job you give them something come
back they haven't done it anyway I had
to to to to to tell somebody to hurry up
now of course I mean in the first month
in the first month in the first month I
had to
and so I then started doing my own
secretarial administrative work and then
one day then I see my sister there she
comes in and she's there in the morning
and she's sitting there and I say what
she says no I'm here to be your PA oh
serious we never negotiated payment
because
[Applause]
in the garage
starting a church leading a church there
yeah people came for counseling
Administration we prayed there in the
garage we used to use the garage to
store instruments that that garage was
many things
it was a practice place it was a storage
place it was a chapel for prayer it was
an office it was a Counseling Center see
when you are starting and when you have
the grace
some of you you need so many things to
get going
you want an office and on the corner
office with glasses and all kinds of
things and and you want so much to start
because you're just not in your
when you have Grace upon you even a
smallanyana thing can be used by God
when when God came to Moses and gave him
his grace Moses are how am I going to do
the Miracles God says what do you have
in your hand
everybody has got something in their
hands come on now everybody has got
something in their hands
no matter how small it may be a garage
it may be an outside room it may be 20
runs in your pocket it may be some
business partner somewhere it may be an
idea it might be a book it might be a
prayer everybody has got something
yeah and when you when you operate in
your area of Grace Paul says I am what I
am and he says it is that Grace that
made me labor more abundantly it is that
Grace that made me apply Excellence at
my work
is that Grace that made me make sure I
don't steal the money is that Grace that
made sure because I'm building
but just those who don't have Grace they
steal they lie they cheat they come late
they live early because they don't have
the grace
because they don't have the grace
they're not build us they just hop along
but they're not Builders but I see you
as a builder in the name of Jesus oh
yeah by the grace of God number what
number seven this is which will be the
last one
I love this one
he says and God is able
to make all grace abound
towards you
God God is able to make all grace abound
always having sufficiency in all things
that you may have an abundance for every
good works let's let's let's let's let's
uh break it down the word abound
describes a river that is overflowing
Paul says
God is able to make
his favor his grace
his divine enablement
to overflow like a river towards you
he makes all grace abound you that you
always having sufficiency in all things
what he's saying is that
in every season that you are going
through in your life
God is able to make his grace overflow
for you
because in this life
we go through many seasons
and it is not our intelligence that kept
us it is not our good planning that kept
us it is not our good speech that kept
us it was the grace of God
and it says God makes that Grace to
overflow
and when that Grace touches you it pulls
you from day to day from strength to
strength from season to season God gave
us Grace when the church was being
attacked God gave us Grace when we lost
our loved ones God gave us Grace when we
lost our job God gave us Grace when our
children were sick God gave us Grace
when our husbands walked away God gave
us Grace when our business was attacked
God gave us Grace when they stole my car
God gave us Grace when people were
talking against me God gives you Grace
that every season that comes they cannot
understand they are not able to destroy
you no matter what they do what they
don't understand is that every day you
are walking in the grace of God from
Christ to Christ from glory to glory
from power to power
and it is not just Grace it's abounding
Grace they can't understand why you have
peace when things are so bad around you
they can't understand why you sing the
Praises of God when you have been so
much trouble they can't understand
what's going on with you they don't know
it is not me who is keeping me it is the
grace of God that is keeping me can I
hear an amen in the house
and God is able to make all grace abound
and that is why you and I because of the
grace of God we will not be afraid of
the Journey of life because life has his
twist as tense life has its Seasons love
has its good times and bad times but we
will rely on the grace of God because we
know the grace of God will abound
towards us
when I'm weak then I'm strong because it
is in the time when I'm weak that the
grace of God is supplied abundantly just
when you think I'm off that's when I'm
starting just when you thought you've
stolen my stuff that's when God is going
to restore because I'm moving in the
grace of God and it's abounding in my
life
David understood that
when he wrote the book of Psalms
chapter 23
the Lord
is my shepherd
I shall not one
he makes me to lie down besides Still
Waters he restores my soul oh he says
and though I walk through the valley of
the shadow of death when I come to that
season and I walk through the valley of
the shadow of death he says I will fear
no evil you know why God because you're
rod and your stuff they comfort me he
said surely goodness and mercy the word
goodness is the word grace is the word
favor he says goodness and mercy follows
me all the days of my life and that's
why I will dwell in the house of the
Lord forever and forever
because through every season
through every season
through every step
God I see your grace
oh God I may be weeping
I may be feeling discouraged but I know
that my Your Grace is surrounding me
I may not have all the all the sauce for
where I'm going but I know that your
grace is surrounding me oh God I may not
feel strong in myself but I know that
your grace is surrounding me and your
grace is abounding towards me that in
all
things shall have sufficiency
and Paul writes that as a man
when he writes about his apostleship
in this book of second Corinthians
he says I've been Shipwrecked
I've been left for dead
I was bitten by a snake
I was chased out of places
and all these things happen to me listen
to me
even if all of that happens to you
the grace of God
and Paul writes and says so I've learned
I've learned
I've learned to be content
well I've got food or I don't have food
I've learned to be content I've learned
to be content whether I have clothes and
I have no clothes I've learned to be
content and the reason I've learned to
be content is that in all these things I
see the grace of God
because when I'm weak
then I'm strong
because that's a dangerous place when
the enemy thinks he's got you when the
enemy says give him one week you will
see what's gonna happen give him two
weeks you will see the business will
close give him one month that your
marriage is gonna break give him six
months it's gonna be the end of them
that is when you are most dangerous
because when you are in that position
that's when the grace of God runs
towards you and covers you and that's
when the grace of God is released in
your life in proportions that you cannot
be able to measure and the grace of God
takes you from stress to strength
Paul says when I'm weak
then I'm strong
and then he writes in Romans 8 8. who
shall separate us
from the love of God
oh who can separate us from the love of
God
is it trial
is it hunger is it demonic principle is
it principality is is it Powers is it
hate is it persecution is it plans and
scheming is it anything he says no all
but you know all these things
we are more than conquerors
through Jesus Christ Our Lord come on
give the Lord
a big praise and a big worship
[Applause]
come on somebody shut up
the grace of God and the goodness of God
it sustains us it raises us up
and the good thing is
it's not silent
it's not quiet
people can see it
and that's why
because they can understand
and that's why they say
you are what you are raise your hands
and Worship the Lord